<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Review &#8211; Badiou&#8217;s Conversations About Theatre Offer Light-Hearted And Quirky Insight Into Mind Of Philosopher (Ryne Beddard)	</title>
	<atom:link href="https://jcrt.org/religioustheory/2016/06/13/review-badious-conversations-about-theatre-offer-light-hearted-and-quirky-insight-into-mind-of-philosopher/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://jcrt.org/religioustheory/2016/06/13/review-badious-conversations-about-theatre-offer-light-hearted-and-quirky-insight-into-mind-of-philosopher/</link>
	<description>E-SUPPLEMENT TO THE JOURNAL FOR CULTURAL AND RELIGIOUS THEORY </description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 21:55:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.21</generator>
			<item>
				<title>
				By: Ann Walker				</title>
				<link>https://jcrt.org/religioustheory/2016/06/13/review-badious-conversations-about-theatre-offer-light-hearted-and-quirky-insight-into-mind-of-philosopher/#comment-2322</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 14:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jcrt.org/religioustheory/?p=361#comment-2322</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[Badiou presents a complete collection of his essays, works, critiques, and interviews spanning over 50 years of his career in writing about films that started while he was still a student. With the main influences being French film, the author has succeeded in trying to bridge the gap between cinema and philosophy, as some of the predecessors such as Gilles Deleuze tried, even though they differ in certain opinions. Badiou’s philosophy insists on the fact that film is an art that represents human life, it thinks, and has universal value to the very existence of freedom.
The cinema allows the human activities to not only be documented, but also become visible. Unlike other forms of art such as paintings that stand still, film tells a story from beginning to end, thus taking the viewer on a journey. Thus, Badiou explains that films think, making it the duty of the person to interpret the meaning of the thought and message contained. Films are also based on people’s lives in many instances, which make it a useful platform for people to be able to relate with throughout time. 
Badiou also explains that cinema is not a pure form of art, as it intersects many ideas and areas of life such as people, politics, and social life. This means that it is one of the best ways to indicate the level, type, and stat of civilisation in a given society. Thus through movies, the society philosophy could be reflected, and thus help to tell the level of civilisation. This review will focus on different critical areas that are included in the book such as author intent, and critical reception among others to aid in providing a reader with a critical and in depth understanding of the  
Badiou is a philosopher intrigued by cinema throughout his career, which has enabled him to write passionate essays and give many interviews that systematically documented his journey of explaining history, change, and philosophy during changing times through the cinemas. Badiou tried to make intellectual interventions throughout the times that cinema and society have changed, especially in France. His journey can be traced from the Sartrean existentialist, top the Maoist, and now to the platonic communism he advocates for in recent days. Badiou admits that Badiou is consistent in the book in explaining his journey and transformation, as well as constantly re inventing the philosophical terms to match the era and cinematic experience offered. 
Badiou understands cinema and films as a way of thinking as well as a resource for thought. This means that the author sees films as a means far beyond what the society uses it for such as entertainment in that it could be applied to judge the level of civility of the society as well as be used as a source of creating proper thinking for development and growth both personally and for the whole society. Badiou admits that in a certain period between 1950 and 1960 he was a cinephile as everyone else was during the era. During the era, many of the philosophers and peers were cinephiles at a very young age and grew into the cinema culture. These include Delueze, Truffaut, Godard, Rivette, Genette, and many more. However, Badiou confesses that he was not a cinephile at a younger age as the rest who found themselves in circles and groups going to cinemas as they grew. Badiou instead became a cinephile much later during his education when he started developing his philosophy through an interest in politics. This is why most of his perspectives on how cinema should be used have interacted with society on political levels as he deems it to be the core reflection of civilisation.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Badiou presents a complete collection of his essays, works, critiques, and interviews spanning over 50 years of his career in writing about films that started while he was still a student. With the main influences being French film, the author has succeeded in trying to bridge the gap between cinema and philosophy, as some of the predecessors such as Gilles Deleuze tried, even though they differ in certain opinions. Badiou’s philosophy insists on the fact that film is an art that represents human life, it thinks, and has universal value to the very existence of freedom.<br />
The cinema allows the human activities to not only be documented, but also become visible. Unlike other forms of art such as paintings that stand still, film tells a story from beginning to end, thus taking the viewer on a journey. Thus, Badiou explains that films think, making it the duty of the person to interpret the meaning of the thought and message contained. Films are also based on people’s lives in many instances, which make it a useful platform for people to be able to relate with throughout time.<br />
Badiou also explains that cinema is not a pure form of art, as it intersects many ideas and areas of life such as people, politics, and social life. This means that it is one of the best ways to indicate the level, type, and stat of civilisation in a given society. Thus through movies, the society philosophy could be reflected, and thus help to tell the level of civilisation. This review will focus on different critical areas that are included in the book such as author intent, and critical reception among others to aid in providing a reader with a critical and in depth understanding of the<br />
Badiou is a philosopher intrigued by cinema throughout his career, which has enabled him to write passionate essays and give many interviews that systematically documented his journey of explaining history, change, and philosophy during changing times through the cinemas. Badiou tried to make intellectual interventions throughout the times that cinema and society have changed, especially in France. His journey can be traced from the Sartrean existentialist, top the Maoist, and now to the platonic communism he advocates for in recent days. Badiou admits that Badiou is consistent in the book in explaining his journey and transformation, as well as constantly re inventing the philosophical terms to match the era and cinematic experience offered.<br />
Badiou understands cinema and films as a way of thinking as well as a resource for thought. This means that the author sees films as a means far beyond what the society uses it for such as entertainment in that it could be applied to judge the level of civility of the society as well as be used as a source of creating proper thinking for development and growth both personally and for the whole society. Badiou admits that in a certain period between 1950 and 1960 he was a cinephile as everyone else was during the era. During the era, many of the philosophers and peers were cinephiles at a very young age and grew into the cinema culture. These include Delueze, Truffaut, Godard, Rivette, Genette, and many more. However, Badiou confesses that he was not a cinephile at a younger age as the rest who found themselves in circles and groups going to cinemas as they grew. Badiou instead became a cinephile much later during his education when he started developing his philosophy through an interest in politics. This is why most of his perspectives on how cinema should be used have interacted with society on political levels as he deems it to be the core reflection of civilisation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
						</item>
			</channel>
</rss>
