<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Review &#8211; Altered States: Buddhism and Psychedelic Spirituality in America (Roger Green)	</title>
	<atom:link href="https://jcrt.org/religioustheory/2016/07/28/review-altered-states-buddhism-and-psychedelic-spirituality-in-america/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://jcrt.org/religioustheory/2016/07/28/review-altered-states-buddhism-and-psychedelic-spirituality-in-america/</link>
	<description>E-SUPPLEMENT TO THE JOURNAL FOR CULTURAL AND RELIGIOUS THEORY </description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 21:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.21</generator>
			<item>
				<title>
				By: David Logan				</title>
				<link>https://jcrt.org/religioustheory/2016/07/28/review-altered-states-buddhism-and-psychedelic-spirituality-in-america/#comment-13772</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Logan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 21:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jcrt.org/religioustheory/?p=462#comment-13772</guid>
					<description><![CDATA[I thought overall this was a pretty good review. However, Green&#039;s criticism that Osto didn&#039;t refer to the &quot;Black Lives Matter Movement&quot;, or that &quot;the bulk of incarcerated people are people of color and thus have more to lose by experimenting with psychedelics and spirituality&quot; is not particularly fair, since Osto makes it clear right from his introduction that he is dealing with a demographic that is predominately white and upper-middle to upper class. He also makes it clear that he is a cultural &quot;insider&quot; to this demographic. It is true that he doesn&#039;t discuss racial inequality, but that&#039;s not the focus of the book. And Osto&#039;s criticisms of the War on Drugs as a political stance would not just benefit white people, but also people of color. Moreover, this statement by Green is highly problematic:

&quot;Perhaps this is an issue of scope; or perhaps it is part of the set and setting of a Grinnell graduate who had the privilege to travel to India after college and then attend Ivy League graduate school after having a mental breakdown, yet still manage to get “gifted and talented” Fullbrights and take part in the MDMA-infused “Harvard Agape.”&quot;

First, it is factually inaccurate. In his postscript, Osto&#039;s autobiography describes how he received a Fulbright to Sri Lanka (not India), experimented with an extremely high dose of Ayurvedic medicine containing cannabis, which caused him to suffered a drug-induced psychosis, then went to Harvard Divinity School (once recovered), and there attended the Harvard Agape. Second, the reference here to Osto&#039;s &quot;set and setting&quot; -- rather than using these terms as they are generally applied to a particular context of a psychedelic experience -- Green uses in an attempt to delegitimize Osto&#039;s  research based on his socio-economic status and mental health, which comes dangerously close to an ad hominem attack.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I thought overall this was a pretty good review. However, Green&#8217;s criticism that Osto didn&#8217;t refer to the &#8220;Black Lives Matter Movement&#8221;, or that &#8220;the bulk of incarcerated people are people of color and thus have more to lose by experimenting with psychedelics and spirituality&#8221; is not particularly fair, since Osto makes it clear right from his introduction that he is dealing with a demographic that is predominately white and upper-middle to upper class. He also makes it clear that he is a cultural &#8220;insider&#8221; to this demographic. It is true that he doesn&#8217;t discuss racial inequality, but that&#8217;s not the focus of the book. And Osto&#8217;s criticisms of the War on Drugs as a political stance would not just benefit white people, but also people of color. Moreover, this statement by Green is highly problematic:</p>
<p>&#8220;Perhaps this is an issue of scope; or perhaps it is part of the set and setting of a Grinnell graduate who had the privilege to travel to India after college and then attend Ivy League graduate school after having a mental breakdown, yet still manage to get “gifted and talented” Fullbrights and take part in the MDMA-infused “Harvard Agape.”&#8221;</p>
<p>First, it is factually inaccurate. In his postscript, Osto&#8217;s autobiography describes how he received a Fulbright to Sri Lanka (not India), experimented with an extremely high dose of Ayurvedic medicine containing cannabis, which caused him to suffered a drug-induced psychosis, then went to Harvard Divinity School (once recovered), and there attended the Harvard Agape. Second, the reference here to Osto&#8217;s &#8220;set and setting&#8221; &#8212; rather than using these terms as they are generally applied to a particular context of a psychedelic experience &#8212; Green uses in an attempt to delegitimize Osto&#8217;s  research based on his socio-economic status and mental health, which comes dangerously close to an ad hominem attack.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
						</item>
			</channel>
</rss>
